

aj2967@hotmail.com





https://www.linkedin.com/in/aj2967/



AJAYBIR SINGH

Junior Web Developer

Profile

An **experienced Web Developer and a BSc (Hons) Computer Science graduate**, skilled in designing websites to meet clients' needs as well as achieving satisfactory outcomes for the organisation. A dedicated individual who is self-motivated and resilient towards their work responsibilities and has a proven record of successfully accomplishing projects for various organisations. Possesses excellent communication and interpersonal skills for meeting the designers, developers and project staff for progress updates. A flexible person, willing to undergo training to build a successful career as a Web Developer.

Education and Qualifications

BSc (Hons) Computer Science | De Montfort University 2020

- Achieved upper second classification (2:1) degree
- Having knowledge of coding different programming languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Php, MySQL
- Worked with databases using MySQL, and different operating systems such as Linux, Windows, MacOS
- Developed a wide range of different software applications during my degree, e.g., a web application with user login and booking system for final year project

A Levels The City of Leicester College 2017

A Level qualification in Business Studies(C), Psychology(D), and ICT(C)

GCSE The City of Leicester College 2015

• 7 GCSE's A-C including English and Math's

Associated Experience

Junior Web Developer | Zustech

February 2022 - Present

- · Collaborate using tools such as MS Teams, Git and Jira to deliver the software
- · Working as a part of a SCRUM team using agile methodology to complete sprints for incremental progress
- Build the front-end of a learning management system with React JS

Junior Web Developer Intern | Future Care (UK) Ltd

February 2021 - April 2021

- Drafted website wireframe designs and documentation based on client's requirements.
- Developed and implemented required pages for the project about creating an interface for baby monitoring devices
- · Implemented a login system for pages with restricted content
- Worked in a team to successfully produce the initial interface and members area for a service that will allow its users to monitor various elements such as temperature of a baby using the baby monitoring device.

Other Experience

Goods In | Lidl

June 2021 - January 2022

- · Took the role of leadership to support colleagues with quality control
- · Quantity checks to match against order sheet

Team Member | KFC

August 2018 - June 2021

- Communicated effectively with customers and colleagues during busy periods.
- Ensured hygiene assurance and quality standards were met when preparing food.
- · Effectively assisted customers to resolve any complaints in a calm and professional manner

Brand Ambassador | 7 Miles Marketing

August 2017 - November 2017

· Liaised with a variety of customers to sell a variety of products to customers

· Provided excellent customer service by learning to interact with the community

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React JS, Php, MySQL, C#

✓ Web Skills: Responsive web design, Bootstrap

✓ Adobe Software: Photoshop, Illustrator

Personal Skills

- ✓ Driving licence with own car
 ✓ Languages: English, Punjabi and Hindi
 ✓ A logical approach to problem solving
 ✓ The ability to work independently and in mixed teams
 ✓ Experience of development methodologies (such as agile and waterfall)
 ✓ The ability to manage a complex range of tasks and meet deadlines
 ✓ Cood communication skills
- Good communication skills

References

Available on request